

GITAU BENSON

- 20321, Nairobi, Kenya
- +254-795-216-928
- bensonkgitau138@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a highly motivated graduate in Civil Aviation Management and software engineering with 3 years of experience at Equity Bank, transitioning from part-time to full-time. I excel in technical, organizational, planning, leadership, accountability, and communication skills. My proficiency includes Python, JavaScript, React, Flask, JSON, SQL, Git, HTML, CSS and Redux Frameworks. I am committed to being a valuable team player, utilizing my diverse skills to drive exceptional results and contribute to organizational success.

EXPERIENCE

RELATIONSHIP OFFICER, 12/2021 - 02/2024 EQUITY BANK KENYA LIMITED RUMURUTI BRANCH

As a relationship officer, I handled filing, cheque clearing, accruals, monthly returns, cash management, and cashiering. I also managed mobile banking onboarding, account openings, and customer service tasks, including mail distribution. These duties have strengthened my organizational skills, financial processing techniques, inventory control, and customer service proficiency.

APPRENTICE, 06/2021 - 08/2021

EQUITY BANK ELDORET MARKET BRANCH

I handled various administrative tasks such as mail management, check verification, credit and insurance sales, Equites SIM card activation, mobile banking setup, and record-keeping, which boosted my sales skills.

MARKETING AGENT, 01/2019 - 04/2021

EQUITY BANK ELDORET MARKET BRANCH, Eldoret

I installed and activated mobile banking apps such as Eazzy Banking and Equity's mobile app. I managed records, handled mail, and addressed customer inquiries, gaining skills in digital banking, customer service, and administration.

SKILLS

Technical Skills:

- Programming: Python (intermediate), JavaScript (intermediate), HTML, CSS

- Frameworks: React, Django, Flask

Databases: MySQL, SQLalchemyVersion Control: Git, GitHub

Soft Skills:

- Problem-solving
- Communication
- Team collaboration
- Time management

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Leadership Experience:

- Branch Trained Fire Marshal, First Aider, and OSHA Committee Member
- Acting Supervisor
- Equity Leadership Program Mentor
- Chapter Leader, Equity Leaders Moi University Chapter (2019, served for 3 years)
- Mentor and Eazzy Products Marketing Training attendee, Equity Group Foundation (2019)
- Dorm Captain, Science Club Member, and Christian Union Member, Lenana School (2016)

EDUCATION

Moringa School, Nairobi, 2024

Full Stack Developer: Software Engineering

Relevant Course: Full Stack Developer

MOI UNIVERSITY. Eldoret. 12/2021

Bachelor of Business Administration: BA Civil Aviation Management

Relevant course: Marketing and Logistics

NAIROBI TECHNICAL AND TRAINING INSTITUTE, Nairobi, 08/2017

Certificate: Computer Proficiecy

Relevant course: Computer proficiency

LENANA SCHOOL, Nairobi, Kenya, 01/2016

Kenya Certificate of High school Education (B plain)

Relevant course: Mathematics (A), Physics (A)

REFERENCES

Mr. Elijah Wanjohi, Operations manager, Equity Bank Eldoret market branch, 0723794035

Charity Gitonga, Cash Officer, Equity Bank Rumuruti Sub-branch, 0723498873

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

- Adventure and traveling
- Coding

- Watching
- Mentorship
- Swimming and workout

CERTIFICATIONS

- · Certified Fire Marshal
- First Aid certification
- Business Presentation
- SQL programming
- Creating and giving business presentations